

Contact



+55 (86) 99591-0997



matheuscosta.tech@gmail.com



My Portfolio



Github



LinkedIn



Parnaíba - PI, Brazil

Languages



English



Portuguese



French (intermediate)

Skills Summary

Python - 3 years+

Html - 3 years+

Css - 3 years+

Django - 3 years+

JavaScript - 3 years+

TypeScript - Used in side projects, 2 years+

jQuery - 2 years+

Bootstrap - 3 years+

React - Used in side projects, 2 years+

Next.js - Used in side projects, 1 year+

Tailwind - Used in side projects, 1 year+

Docker - 3 years+

Dart - Used in side projects, 1 year+

Flutter - Used in side projects, 1 year+

Matheus Costa

FULL-STACK ENGINEER

About Me

I'm a passionate software developer with **3 years of experience** in Python and JavaScript. I've had the pleasure of diving into technologies like **jQuery**, **Django**, **React**, **and TypeScript**, and I feel right at home with Linux and Docker.

Experience

Higia Health Technology

March 2022 - Present

- Development of a speech-to-writing translation module (using the Web Speech API), making it possible to dictate the medical report
- Module to manage customizable common phrases that the radiologist could configure both voice and text commands for greater productivity
- Report lifeline graph, showing how long it took at each stage when preparing the medical report
- Development of profiling tools
- Performance improvements using profiling tools to identify bottlenecks in database queries, libraries that could be replaced, unnecessary requests, and so on
- Various other improvements in existing features and creation of new ones

State University of Piauí - UESPI

February 2021 - March 2022

- Development and maintenance of a REST api that served data to a mobile application to manage some internal processes at the university related to the student
- Writing automated integration and unit tests
- Deploy in docker with nginx, uwsgi and django

Education

State University of Piauí

2019 - Present

Bachelor of Computer Science

Harvard University

2020 - 2021

CS50 Web Programming with Python and JavaScript

High school in Parnaíba

2016 - 2018

Computer Technician